《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break
-东西在哪?   -你去死
-Where is it?   -Go to hell.
这是你自找的
You did this to yourself.
莎拉 如果你在听的话
Sara, if you're listening,
现在只希望你能找到安全的避难所
I only hope,by now, you've found your safe haven.
我利用了你 置你于一个
I took advantage of you, put you in a place
对每个医生来说都是噩梦的境地
that's every doctor's nightmare.
莎拉·唐克雷蒂 你了解吗?
Sara Tancredi. You know her well?
如果你能把我调到隔离监狱  我对她的了解会更深
I'd know her a lot better if you can get my ass moved.
我会跟狱长商量看
I'll talk to the warden.
"另一次机会"和"安全避难所"
"Another chance" and "safe haven."
这都是出自一本有名的书
Those are the names of
这些词都出自那"酗酒无名氏"的章节名
some of the chapters in the book they use an aa.
别乱来
Make no mistake about it.
我们死都要在一起
We will be a family if it kills us.
那就是你的地图?
That's your map?
你的手腕怎么了?
What happened to your arm?
我爸爸也是个酒鬼
My dad drinks, too.
我肚子痛
My tummy hurts.
她需要那药 没药她走不了两天
She needs that medicine. She can't go two days without it.
基斯的案子就要审判了
Kacee's going into the system now.
再加一条叛逃罪
Aiding an escaped con.
告诉她律师我会自首
Tell her lawyer I'll turn myself in.
基斯说你得赶紧跑
Kacee said you need to run.
如果你被抓了或自首了
If you get busted or turn yourself in,
迪迪就没爹没娘了
Dede won't have either of you.
迈克尔 我想让这一切结束
Michael, I want for this to be over.
我们都想让这结束
That makes two of us.
但我们得看你父亲到底给你留了什么
It's just a question of looking at whatever it is your father gave you.
就只有一个钥匙
It's just a key.
必要的话 可以利用下总统...
If I may, sir, the president... she could be useful.
总统?
Madam president?
我想让你回来 保罗
I want you to come home, Paul.
我们能搞定的
We can fix this,
我不要你带这那两兄弟到处乱来
but not with those brothers running around the country.
凯若琳...
Caroline...
把他们交给我 保罗
bring them in, Paul,
之后一切就可恢复原样了
and everything can go back to the way it was.
保罗 克里曼探员
Agent Kellerman.
保罗 你在哪?
Paul, where are you?
在个没人管的地方 不记得了?
Out in the cold. Remember?
今晚我要在芝加哥发表演说
I'm speaking in Chicago tonight.
林肯
Lincoln.
莎拉
Sara.
真是有趣 当你需要我了才打电话给我
It's funny how you only call me when you need me.
也许有趣这个词用的并不恰当
Maybe "funny" is not the right word.
这些都可解决的 保罗
All of this can go away, Paul.
是吗?
Can it?
当然 我是美国总统
Yes.I'm the president of the united states.
回芝加哥来吧
Please just come back to Chicago
把布伦斯和斯科菲尔德交给我
and turn Burrows and Scofield in.
我答应你 我会让一切恢复原样
I promise you that I will make everything go back to the way it was.
我得挂了
I have to go.
回来吧 保罗
Just come back, Paul.
我需要你
I need you.
你认为我们手上握有筹码?
You actually think we have a shot?
那得看你爸留给了你什么
It depends on what your father gave you.
这是我找到他时从他口袋掉出来的
This fell out of his pocket when I found him.
我认不出这个标志 你呢?
I don't recognize the insignia, do you?
不认识
No.
但是 呃...
But, uh...
莎拉 我们现在有个合伙人
Sara, we've got someone working with us now.
早上好啊 阳光灿烂的早晨
good morning, sunshine.
睡的如何?
How did you sleep?
让我来告诉你
I'll tell you what.
我会让孩子们出来 然后给大家弄早饭
I'll go unlock the kids and make us all breakfast.
不 我去给孩子们开门
No. I'll get the kids.
-不...    -嘘 我去
-No...    -tu-tut-tut. I insist.
不
No.
我去把孩子们叫来
I'll get the kids.
涂些润肤霜会让瘀伤好一点
Some hand cream will make them rope burns feel better.
没用的
It won't work.
当然有用了
'Course it will.
看这上面写的 缓解皮肤伤痛和...
Says right here on the bottle: "Soothes skin irritations and..."
不 这个
No. This.
这没用的 我得去工作
It won't work.I've got a job.
孩子们得上学
The kids have school.
在这段小小的适应期过后
We're all going to get back to our normal routines
一切都会回复正常的
once this little adjustment period is over.
今天有人会过来
There's someone coming over today.
谁?
Who?
一个女的 帕蒂
This woman, Patty,
欢乐购协会的人
from the welcome wagon committee.
打电话给她取消
Call her and cancel.
我没她的电话
I don't have her number.
如果她来了 我又不去开门
And,if she shows up,and I don't answer the door,
她会发觉有点不对劲的
she's going to know something's wrong.
泰迪...
Teddy...
泰迪熊...
Teddy bear...
你得走了
you need to go.
如果她认出你的话...
If she recognizes you...
我不想你惹麻烦上身
I don't want you to get in trouble.
胡说
That's nonsense.
没什么麻烦
It's no trouble.
什么麻烦都不会有
No trouble at all.
嗨 莎拉
Hi, Sara.
过去的就让他过去吧
What's done is done.
我们目标一致啊
We all want the same thing.
你没告诉我们你想让她死
You didn't tell us you left her to die.
我只是吓吓她
I was scaring her.And I could pull her out.
不 不 你想淹死我
No. No, you left me in there to drown.
我倒想看看你能屏住呼吸多久
I wonder how long you can hold your breath.
我们来试试看
Maybe we should find out.
你们需要我 你们知道的
You need me, and you know it.
你们需要我 你们需要我 你知道的
You need me. You need me, and you know it.
为什么? 我们为何需要他? 钥匙在我们手上
Why? Why do we need him?We have the key.
我们会找出究竟是什么东西
We'll find out what it's for.
我现在就可以告诉你们是什么东西
I can tell you what that key's for right now.
这是一个私人雪茄俱乐部的钥匙
It's to a private cigar club.
哪?
Where?
芝加哥
Chicago.
我们得快点了
We have to hurry.
我们得快点 拉瑞
We have to hurry, Larry.
我做了坏事
I did a bad thing.
天哪!我做了件很不好的事
God! I did a very bad thing.
80 30 77公路上的所有加油站
All gas stations On 80, 30, 77.
我要斯科菲尔德和布伦斯的照片贴满每一个加油站
I want Scofield's and Burrows' pictures on each and every gas pump.
-没油他们哪都去不             -长官?
-If they have no fuel,they can't get anywhere.  -Sir?
-什么事?  -我们或许得把我们的注意力
-What?    -We might need to divert our attention away
从斯科菲尔德和布伦斯身上转移开一会儿了
from Scofield and Burrows for a while.
为什么我得那样做
Why would I do that?
因为另外一个逃犯刚刚杀了一个公民
Because one of the other escapees just killed a civilian.
一个符合这样描述的人
A man fitting his description was spotted
满身血迹地从残忍的杀人现场逃脱
running from the scene of a brutal homicide.
就发生在埃尔戈马 威斯康辛
Happened in Algoma, Wisconsin,
从监狱里逃出来不到四小时
less than four hours from the prison.
给麦迪逊办公室打电话
Call the field office in Madison,
让他们立刻找一些特工去那儿
and have them get some agents out there right away.
我马上报告总局
Okay.I'll notify headquarters.
我没有说总局
I didn't say headquarters.
我说 难道你不服从指挥
I said, are you not following direct orders?
我服从 长官
Oh, I am following direct orders, sir.
只不过现在不再服从你了
Just not from you anymore.
从现在开始所有事件都要听从总部
Everything goes through headquarters from now on.
可以吗
may I?
恩
yeah.
你听说帕托塞克的事了
You heard about Patoshik.
就在刚刚
Just now.
很好
Good.
他跑了
He goes.
他是个精神病
Come on, the man is mentally ill.
他什么都不知道 他并不是个威胁
He doesn't know anything, he's not a threat...
帕托塞克当过一阵子斯科菲尔德的同房囚犯
Patoshik was one of Scofield's cellmates for awhile.
斯科菲尔德把他列在逃跑计划中
Scofield included him in the escape.
谁知道他知道些什么
Who knows what he knows?
可斯科菲尔德和布伦斯还在逃
Scofield and Burrows are still out there.
现在不用担心斯科菲尔德和布伦斯
Don't worry about Scofield and Burrows right now.
好 再一次
So, again...
帕托塞克
Patoshik goes.
小心点
Take care of it.
你负责这节车厢的座位?
Hi, are you in charge of seating?
有什么我能帮您
Yeah, can I help you?
保罗克里曼探员  特工部门
Agent Paul Kellerman, Secret Service.
我要把一个逃犯运到芝加哥
I'm transporting a fugitive to Chicago.
我需要你给我一节空的车厢
I need you to clear a car for me.
- 一个逃犯?      - 哦 是的
- A fugitive?    - Yes,that's right.
只是
Well,
我们的车厢快坐满了
it's just that we're already near capacity...
你希望他碰到你的其他乘客?
you want him to rub elbows with your other passengers?
-不 长官    -好吧
-No, sir.   -Okay.
他以什么罪名被通缉
What's he wanted for?
杀人
Killing people.
天哪
Good lord. Make it happen.
那确实发生了
Make it happen.
好吧 来吧 跟着我
All right, come on, follow me.
一切都会没事的
It's gonna be all right.
如果你这么认为的话
If you say so.
利用他帮我们得到我们需要的
We use him to get what we need,
然后就甩掉他
then we dump him.
好的
Okay.
我很抱歉你被卷到这件事里
I'm sorry you got involved in this.
事实上你对我们的帮助
The fact that you're helping us...
意义重大
means a lot.
谢谢
Thank you.
其他的乘客不会遇到危险吧?
The other riders aren't in any danger, are they?
我的意思是 我们是不是应该发布个公告什么的
I mean, should I make an announcement or anything?
你希望这里变得一片混乱?
You want pandemonium?
-不 长官   -好 不发布公告
-No,sir.  -Okay,then no announcements,right?
只要让所有人远离这节车厢就行了
Just keep everybody out of this car
那就万事大吉了
then everything is jake.
我做这事儿都几百万次了
I've done this a million times.
从没发生过什么事
Never had a problem.
好的 我照办
Okay, will do.
好了 我们走
Let's go.
我们大概要花五个小时到芝加哥
We'll be in Chicago in about five hours.
想要休息会儿吗?
Want to get some rest.
你还好吗?
You okay?
恩
Yeah.
光头
Brad.
你看上去不是很好
You don't look too good.
我帮你搞定了莎拉·唐克雷蒂的事
I helped you with Sara Tancredi,
你应该把我弄到隔离监狱去
and you were supposed to get me into AD Seg.
我试过了
I tried.
但是你的新监狱长...
But your new warden... Mm...
是一个道德上循规蹈矩的人
straight as an arrow.
但是我可以帮你弄到 一个比隔离监狱更好的地方
But I might be able to do you one better than AD Seg.
你通过俄罗斯女孩 发现了斯科菲尔德和布伦斯是吗?
You found Scofield and Burrows through the Russian girl,right?
是的 尼卡 怎么了
Yeah, Nika. Why?
你还通过追踪苏珊 霍兰德 来追捕巴格威尔
And you tracked down Bagwell by following Susan Hollander.
是的 我用右手擤鼻涕
Yeah.And I blow my nose with my right hand
左手擦我的屁股
and I wipe my ass with my left.
怎么了
What of it?
我有个很有权势的后台
I've got very powerful people behind me
他希望我赶快结束这项工作
that want me to finish my job.
只要他们说一句话
They can push through the quickest habeas
法院就能以前所未见的速度
corpus proceedings the courts have ever seen.
通过人身保护权行动程序
Paperwork's sitting on the right
然后就能保释外出
person's desk as we speak,
你违法宪法的控诉
setting forth all the constitutional violations in your prosecution.
你就等着消除得一干二净
It's just waiting to be rubber-stamped.
那我需要做什么?
And what do I have to do?
你只需要找到那些逃犯
You just find those cons.
只是这次
Only, this time...
你是帮我做这个
you're gonna do it for me--
非公认的 没有正式公文
unofficially,under the radar,no paper trail...
我需要一只专门处理垃圾的狗去做那些脏事
I need a junkyard dog who's willing to do
将那些犯人绳之以法
the ugly things it takes to bring a con to justice.
你愿意成为我的走狗 光头?
Are you my dog, Brad?
他妈的 好吧 我同意
Damn hell, yeah, I am.
这真好吃
This is delicious.
你把它叫什么?
What'd you call it again?
那个 我最爱的派对蛋糕
That, my dear Patty-cake,
我阿姨回巴马时曾经叫它"流浪鸡"
is what my auntie back in 'bama used to call "hobo chicken.
一份鸡肉 两份辣椒 三份真实的流浪生活
One part chicken,two parts spice,three part actual hobo.
我知道...家禽
I know, uh, uh...fowl
不是传统的每日早中餐的一部分
isn't part of a traditional brunch, per se,
但我发现缺少肉类
but I have found a lean meat can
就像缺少开胃酒...
act as an aperitif to, uh...
会让餐盘失去了...
awaken the pallet
食物的香味以及松软可口
for more subtle flavors and textures,
就像...
such as...
天哪
mama mia!
南瓜肉桂面包
Pumpkin cinnamon breads with
新鲜草莓和冰淇淋
fresh strawberries and cream.
哦 孩子们
Oh, boy!
你们俩怎么遇到的
Now, how did you two meet?
在教堂
Church.
恩
en
在我出了意外之后
after my, uh...accident,
我和其他那些受切断手术的人 一起参加志愿活动
uh, I was volunteering with some other amputees.
我回到教区
My parish back home
在教会间搞联谊活动
did an exchange program with churches
这个美好的乡村...
all over this fine country and...
老天爷!
well...
看到一个适合我的地方
the good lord just saw fit to plop my country rump
刚巧就在我的可爱的苏珊边上的长凳坐了下来
right down in the pew beside my susie Q.
然后你就偷走了她的心
And you just stole her heart.
我是一个普通的独臂强盗
I'm a regular one-armed bandit.
独臂强盗
A one-armed bandit...
华莱士太太 泰迪叔叔给我买了辆新自行车
Mrs.Wallace, Teddy just bought me a brand-new bike.
在车库 想去看看吗?
It's out in the garage. Wanna go see?
好啊
Sure.
我们正聊得好好的
We have got company.
没关系
Oh, that's okay.
这样不行 这样太不礼貌了  扎克 知道该怎么做
No,it's not; it's rude. Zack knows better.
对吧
Isn't that right?
你知道该怎么做 扎克
You do know better, Zack.
你需要有些规矩
you gotta have discipline.
如果没有一个强硬的父亲形象
Without a strong father figure,
一个年轻人会在监狱中度过余生
a young man might just end up in prison.
看在你那么喜欢吃蓝莓派 自己不会做只能上商店去买
since you are such a fan of lame store-bought blueberry pie,
我今天亲手给你做一个
I am gonna bake you a real pie...
我的名字兰斯 我是个瘾君子
hi, my name's Lance and I'm an addict.
兰斯 你好
Hi, Lance.
嗨 莎拉
Hi, Sara.
其实我的名字不是兰斯 我也不是瘾君子
Hi,my name is not Lance,I'm not an addict.
迈克尔
hey, Michael...
你知道哪儿有水吗?
do you know if there's any way I can get any water?
楼下的卫生间应该有吧
Yeah, I think there's a bathroom downstairs.
-我去看看     -谢了
-I'll check.  -Thanks.
那次不是个人恩怨 莎拉
It was never personal, Sara
这次斗争也不是
war never is.
莎拉! 莎拉!
Sara! Sara!
你还想再杀我一次 看看
you get one of those!
来!
One.
坐下来 马上给我坐好!
Get down, right now.
发生什么事?
What?
那三个人说他们看到
These three guys said they saw
你们快要打起来了
what looked to be a fight going on in there.
你看 我们很好 只要让火车快点到芝加哥就行了
They didn't,all right? Just get the train to Chicago.
需要我去叫警察来吗?
Do I need to notify the police?
你只要做好我刚才叫你做的事就行了
You need to do what I just told you to do.
你收你的票我 我来看好这群亡命之徒
You take the tickets, I'll watch the fugitive.
你们在外面想怎么吵
You guys can just continue to do bong hits,
或者你们在那想怎么闹就怎么闹?
or whatever you do back there, okay?
管好你们自己的事情 知道了吗?
Now would you guys mind your own business?
都听清楚了吗?
Everybody clear?
非常好
Great.
别再进来打搅我们了
Don't interrupt again, please.
我想我们都应该清楚
Just so we're all clear:
如果她还想杀死我的话
If she tries that again...
你要干什么?
you'll do what?
你先在那排座位上待着吧
Just stay on the other side of the car.
保罗 这不是个人恩怨
It wasn't personal, Paul.
这是什么?
What're these?
我...
Oh, I'm, uh...
做了些整修
gonna do some renovations.
我刚才在钉这个石膏板 还差一个螺钉
Uh, I was just tappin' the sheetrock,lookin' for the stud.
似乎你已经找到了
Looks like you already found one.
好大一张嘴
Potty mouth!
我和那些女孩每周五都会在书吧聚会
Me and the girls get together every friday for book club.
你应该来主持这周的聚会 这样大家都可以认识你了
You ought to host it this week and everybody can meet you.
而且我也可以再次看到你
I'll see you then!
我都等不及了
Can't wait.
不能再在这里待了
this ain't ever gonna work here.
去收拾你们的东西 我们准备要搬家
Go pack your things, we're movin'
如果你继续不理我的话
If you don't stop me,
我就把这些好吃的都吃掉
I'm gonna eat this whole thing by myself.
好吧 宝贝 听我说
All right, sweetie,listen.
我和你打个商量怎么样
I'll make a deal with you.
还记得我们今天看到的那个旋转木马吗?
Remember that merry-go-round that we saw today?
如果你不把这些东西吃了的话
You're not gonna get a chance to ride it,
你就没有机会去玩了  快吃吧
if you don't eat something. Go ahead.
我有点不舒服
I don't feel good.
哦 宝贝
Oh, sweetie.
好了 振作点
Okay, come on.
我们走吧 好吗?
Let's go, all right?
我抱你
I got you.
好了 稍微等下 是要甜豆吗?
Okay, just hold on. Okay, sweet pea?
结帐
Check, please?
听着! 所有人都不准动!
All right! Nobody move!
莎拉 在吗?
Hey, Sara?
我想一个人待会
Not now
她怎么样了?
how is she?
她想一个人静静
Well, she wants to be alone.
我们用钥匙拿到她父亲藏的东西后
So we get what her dad locked away with that key.
接下来我们怎么办?
What do we do then?
我是说... 你也看到了他们是如何分析那个录象带
I mean... you saw what they did with the tape we made.
他们会把我们揭露出来的事情都处理好的
They're gonna bury everything we put out there.
这就是我们为什么把他留在身边的原因
That's why we're keeping him close to us.
他在华盛顿有很多的关系
He's got a lot of connections in washington.
如果我们去雪茄俱乐部 打开她父亲的箱子
So we get to the cigar club,open her dad's box...
却只是找到了一大堆的雪茄 怎么办?
what if the only thing inside's a bunch of stogies?
我觉得它值得我们去弄个明白
I think it's worth making the trip to find out.
你好?
Yes?
凯若琳
Caroline.
保罗 你在哪儿?
Paul. Where are you?
我想知道你确切的意思
I need to know exactly what you meant
你说会把事情处理好
when you said you were gonna make this right.
我要听具体点的
I need specifics.
你在哪儿? 你周围的是什么声音?
Where are you? What's that noise?
我在火车上 一会就到芝加哥了
I'm on a train. I'll be in Chicago later today.
我要知道具体点的东西
But I need to know specifics.
布伦斯和斯科菲尔德在哪?
Where are Burrows and Scofield?
他们和你在一起吗?
Are they with you?
不用那么担心他们 关心关心我吧
Don't worry about them,worry about me.
保罗 在我的部门里还有很多职位的空缺
Paul,there are still positions in my administration
无论是主管还是职员都需要人
that need to be filled--including chief of staff.
我希望你会参与进来
I want that to be you.
当我到了芝加哥 我会去见你
When I get to Chicago, we'll meet.
到时候再谈
We'll talk.
把全部都拿出来
all of it.
伙计 我就带了买三明治的钱
Man, I just brought enough to get a sandwich.
当时我就坐在那儿  真的
I was sitting right there, okay?
如果你说谎...
If you're lying...
你看我女儿生病了
look, my daughter is sick,
我不想在这里浪费太多时间
and I don't want to spend any more minutes in here than necessary.
相信我 这是我所有的东西了
Trust me, that is all that I have.
宝贝 你有什么东西吗?
What do you got, sweetheart?
你有什么东西?
What do you got?
你敢不听话?!
You don't want to listen?!
嘿 嘿 冷静点 伙计
Hey, hey, calm down, man.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
好吧
All right.
听我说 你要冷静点
Listen to me, you've got to calm down.
好吧 我帮你拿你想要的东西
All right, I can help you get everything that you want.
你也不想伤害任何人 对吧?
But you don't want to hurt anybody else, right?
来吧
Come on.
听我说
Look, listen.
你先去前面把门锁上好吗?
Why don't you go ahead and lock the door,
然后把"停止营业"的牌子挂上
and turn the closed sign back,
那别人就会觉得这里已经关门了 是吧?
so everybody thinks that this place is closed, all right?
然后让大家都离窗户远点儿
And then, we can get everybody away from the window
这样做你能放心点了吗?
Is that cool with you?
大家都离窗户远点 好吗?
Everybody's away from the window, okay?
大家快行动起来都到那边去
Let's move everybody onto this side of the room.
去那边 大家快
Get on this side of the room, everybody.
到那边去 离窗户远点
Let's move to this side of the room from the window.
快!大家都到那边去好吗?
Move!Everybody,let's get on this side of the room, okay?
去那边
This side of the room.
把我女儿也带过去 好吗?
Why don't you take my daughter, okay?
把她带到那边去
Take her on this side of the room, so that everybody...
所有人都会没事的
everything is gonna be okay.
一切都会好的
Everything is gonna be fine.
现在你不用对任何人开枪了 是吧?
Because you're not gonna put your hand on another person, right?
对吧?
Right.
没错 我们做的不错
We're all good.
是的
Yeah
我们做的很好?
all good?
我们做的很好 是吧?
We're good, right?
嘿 莎拉?
Hey, Sara?
进来吧
Come on in.
嘿
hey
我一直坐在这里想
I've been sitting here evaluating.
我...
I, uh...
我在保释中逃走
I jumped bail.
并被通缉
I'm on the run,
而且我刚刚还想杀死一个人
and I just tried to take a man's life.
我真没用
I'm not using.
而这些就是我的所做所为
Which is actually quite an accomplishment.
但是在三个星期前 我还是个医生
But three weeks ago, I was a doctor.
你可以把失去的东西都拿回来
You can get that back...all of it.
你要坚定信心
You need to believe that.
你真的那么认为吗?
You believe that?
你能把失去的东西都找回来吗?
You think you can get it all back?
我选择去相信
I choose to have faith.
如果我不相信 我就完了
Because without that, I'm nothing.
这是唯一支持我做下去的动力
It's the only thing that's keeping me going.
是啊...有两件事让我一直坚持到现在
I got two things keeping me going.
第一是我要找到杀害我父亲的凶手
First, is that I want the people who killed my dad.
然后第二件就是...
And actually, the second...
真讽刺 也许我不应该说是谁害死了他
ironically, I probably wouldn't even say
如果我没有失去他的话 而且...
if I hadn't lost him, but, um...
你知道...
you should know that...
呃...
um...
当我选择这个工作的时候 人们告诉我的第一件事
the first thing they tell you when you take the job,
就是...
is, um,
不要爱上犯人
never to fall in love with an inmate.
林肯 锁上了
Linc  It's locked.
你不可以进来
You can't be in here.
冲过去
run the roadblock.
大哥 我可不敢
Man, I can't do that.
冲!
Run it!
布拉德利·贝利克 FBI
Bradley Bellick, FBI.
布拉德利·贝利克 联邦调查局
Brad Bellick, federal bureau of investigations.
布拉德利·贝利克 FBI
Brad Bellick, FBI.
布拉德利·贝利克 FBI特工
Special agent Brad Bellick, FBI.
你好 我是FBI的布拉德利·贝利克
Hi, there, I'm Brad Bellick with the FBI.
我是FBI的布拉德利·贝利克特工
I'm an agent with the FBI, Brad Bellick.
布拉德利·贝利克 调查局的
Brad Bellick. I'm with the bureau.
Brad Bellick. I'm with the Bureau.
我已经跟警察说过了 该说的都说了
I already talked to the cops, told them all I had to say.
我可不是那些草包警察
Yeah, well, I'm no local hayseed cop.
我是FBI
I'm federal.
你别想骗骗我就了事
And you're not going to get away with lying to me.
我没骗人
I didn't lie to nobody.
是吗?
Really?
他不过是个在汉考克广场游荡的流浪汉
He was just some homeless guy,hangs around hancock square,
靠从高中生出乞讨为生
hitting up college kids for change.
他一直在那附近
He's down there all the time.
要不是在那里 我也不知道哪儿去找他
If he's not there, I don't know where to find him."
是不是你的口供?
That's your statement, right?
差不多
Pretty much.
哼 其实查尔斯 海威 帕托塞克
Right.See, the problem is Charles "Haywire" Patoshik
是个偏执狂 对人多的地方相当恐惧
is a paranoid,who suffers from fear of crowds,
尤其怕陌生人
who's terrified of strangers.
他要在也是在无人之境
If he's anywhere, he's in the middle of nowhere,
安分守己地当个怪胎
keeping to himself, being a weirdo.
-然后?   -如果你想来点硬的...
-And?    -And if you want to get tough...
不如我现在告你妨碍公务
how about I arrest you right now
把你抓起来如何?
for hindering a federal investigation?
谁会相信你?
Who they going to believe?
一个当差15年
An agent with 15 years on the force
并且3次由总统授勋的特工
and three presidential citations
还是一个进过少教所的小娘们?
or a piece of white trash with a juvie record?
我没让他这么做 但是怕你没注意到
I didn't ask him to do it,but in case you haven't noticed,
我对我继父的死
I ain't exactly broken up
并不是那么难过
over my stepdad's death.
你为什么就不能放过帕托塞克这个家伙呢?
Why can't you just leave this Patoshik guy alone?
他在哪里?
Where is he?
还是你想现在就被铐起来?
Or do you want to get locked up...
有帕托塞克的线索了
I got a lead on Patoshik.
哪里?
Where?
我这就来
I'm on my way.
拖住他
Keep him there.
让他走单
Alone.
任何关于斯科菲尔德和布伦斯的消息
Any information on Scofield and Burrows,
马上通知我
I want to be notified immediately.
如果能劳您大驾的话
If that works out for you.
下一站会有警察在等我们
They're gonna have cops waiting for us at the next station.
那我们得跳车
We need to jump then.
然后呢?
And do what?
躲到酒桶里去?
Hide under a barrel?
林肯说得对
Linc's right.
好的 你放在这里吧
Okay, you just put those in there.
真是对不起了
I'm so sorry about all this.
没事的 宝贝
It's okay, sweet pea.
老弟 都在这里了
Here's everything right here, man.
好了
It's good.
听着 都到贮藏室去
All right, everyone in the storage room.
快
Now.
什么?
What?
回去待着一直到警察来
Get back there until the cops show up.
不行不行 我不能回去
No, no, no, no, I can't go back there.
-走吧      -不行
-Come on.  -No.
听着 你刚才一直都很冷静
Look, you kept a cool head this whole time.
别让我现在杀了你
Don't get yourself killed now.
你知道吗?听我说
You know what?Listen to me.
我被通缉了
I'm a wanted man.
要是警察来了 我就得回牢里
If the police show up here,they'll take me back to prison,
你知道吗?这没什么大不了的
and you know what?That's fine.
但是我女儿就在这里 她病了
But my little girl right here? She's sick.
我进去了 她就剩她自己了
And she's going to be left alone.
我不能被抓走
And I can't let that happen,
你能不能放我们走?
so can you please let us go?
走吧!
Go!
这边 咱们走吧
Come on.This way.Let's go.
听好 所有人都到后面去
all right, everyone in the back.
动起来
Move.
-你不用走   -不!
-Not you.   -No!
你跟着我
You're coming with me.
快 动起来
Go on.Move.
你就在这里站着好不?
Okay, I want you to stay right here, okay?
快!
Go on!
我认为你应该让他走 老弟
Hey.I think you should let her go, man.
消失 最后的机会
take off.Last chance.
你已经拿到了钱
You've got the money.
盗窃和人身攻击
Burglary and assault
老弟 这可是是有区别的 抢劫那不过是小儿科
Man, hey, that's change, man, that's little time.
但是你现在干的
But this right here...
是够让你在监狱里
you will be in prison
过完下半辈子的
for the rest of your life.
相信我
Believe me on that.
除非你想让你女儿看到你死
Unless you want your daughter to see you die,
快滚
move.
嘿 我是在帮你
I'm trying to help you, man!
来吧
come here!
宝贝 站在那别动
sweetie, stay right there.
噢 不是吧
oh, no.
这是谁干的?
who did this?
是我
I did.
怎么样了?
谢谢
Thank you.
海威!
Haywire!
不许动!
Don't move!
快跑 拉瑞 快点 拉瑞
Run!Larry!Run!
快点
Hurry!Hurry!
迪诺 我是艾里克
Dino, it's Eric.
有四个乘客跳车了
We've got four jumpers.
三个男的和一个女的
Three males and a female.
快通知警方
Call it in
然后把火车停在下一站
and get us to the next station.
听到了没有?
Do you hear me?
快在下一站停车
Get us to the next station.
强迫冲破路障的那几个人跳车了
The men who pushed through the roadblock are jumping off
火车正接近54里标
the train near mile marker 54,just south of the Tedford bridge.
站住! 别开枪
freeze! Don't shoot!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
转过身来
Turn around!
我们是铁路公司的职员
I'm an employee of the train company.
迪诺 我是艾里克 有四个乘客跳车了
Dino, it's Eric. We've got four jumpers.
三个男的和一个女的
Three males and a female.
快通知警方 然后把火车停在下一站
Call it in and get us to the next station.
跳下去 快
Let's go. Come on.
是他们让我们跳车然后往外跑的
They told us to jump and run
而且要我们跑的时候不要回头 如果我们不这么做他们就会开枪
and not to look back or they'd shoot us.
我们得找辆车
We need to find a car.
怎么了?
yeah
我把海威逼到一个塔上去了
I got Haywire trapped.
不要采取任何行动
Don't do anything.
看住他 我很快就到
Just hold him until I get there.
没问题 他已经孤立无援了
No problem. I got this wingnut treed.
凯若琳
Caroline.
保罗 你在哪?
Paul, where are you?
刚刚是你派的警察?
Did you send the police?
没有 当然不是
No, of course not.
那他们怎么知道我在火车上
How did they know I was on that train?
保罗 我一点也不知道
Paul, I have no idea.
我会转达总统的
I'll let the president know.
我直接和总统联系
I contact the president directly.
布伦斯和斯科菲尔德是不是和你在一起
Are Burrows and Scofield with you?
我等着向总统汇报
I was expecting to brief the president.
你现在向我汇报就可以了
You report to me now.
保罗?
Paul?
我35岁生日 我们是在哪里过的?
Where did we spend my 35th birthday?
什么
What?
那家饭店
The restaurant.
你想起来在哪了吗
Where was it?You remember.
不要这么荒唐 我要挂了
Don't be ridiculous.I have to go.
别挂电话
Do not hang up.
我得挂了
I have to go.
抓住布伦斯和斯科菲尔德...
Just get Burrows and Scofield...
嘿
hey.
不管是谁
Whoever this is...
告诉比尔·金是他亲手毁掉了...
tell bill kim that he just screwed up...
好时光
big-time.
保罗?
Paul?Paul?
这都是怎么了
What's all this?
那疯子爬上了谷仓
Some whacko climbs up to a grain elevator,
人们在围观
people want to watch.
上帝啊 你本应该处理好这事儿的
oh, god, you we supposed to keep a handle on things.
你不明白吗?
Do you know what that means?
我给你抓到了海威 你还想要什么?
I got you Haywire. What else do you want?
联邦调查局 他是我的承押记人
FBI. He's my chargee.
你好啊 查尔斯
How you doing, Charles?
我不想再回监狱
I don't want to go back to prison.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我想去荷兰
I want to go to Holland.
我可真没想到
That's not what i expected to hear.
但是孩子 你不可能到那里
But you can't go there, son.
我只是...
I just...
我就是想要去... 这个地方
I just want to go...here.
看
See?
我跟你说
Yeah.I'll tell you what.
你可以不用进监狱
You don't have to go to prison.
当然你还是不可能到荷兰的
But you can't go to Holland, either.
-哦 不不不...    -没关系
-Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no. -It's okay,
没关系
it's okay, it's okay.
现在你身处绝境
Hey, you're in a tough spot.
你感到内外交困 你发现无路可走
You feel trapped, you got no options, and...
陷入这样的地步 你自己也无能为力
caught in a situation where you have no control.
我明白你的感受
I know how you feel.
真的
I do.
痛苦不断磨你  你唯一能做的只有逃跑
It takes its toll on you, and all you want to do is run.
但是逃向哪去呢
But run where?
我就是想要离开
I just want to go.
有一条出路的
There's a way out.
一条出路?
A way out?
对
Yeah.
从这座迷宫之中?
Of this maze?
对
Yeah.
后面是私人的烟草贮藏室
There are private humidors in the back.
每个会员的盒子上都有自己的名字
Each member's name is on their box.
有没有警卫把守?
Any security?
只有一名招待员在那
A receptionist.That's it.
我不是通缉犯
I'm not a wanted fugitive.
给我钥匙  我去吧
Give me the key.I'll do it.
你想不想一起去走走
Want to take a walk?
恩
Yeah.
我知道你是由于受到父母的伤害
I know you killed your parents
才杀了他们的
because they hurt you.
我也知道你昨天杀的那个人是因为
And I know you killed that guy yesterday
他伤害了萨沙 但是你这么做...
because he was hurting Sasha, but what you did...
是错的
was wrong.
你要明白
You know that.
我只是想离开
I just want to go.
你可以的
You can.
我现在就想离开
I want to go now.
没关系
it's okay.
萨拉
Sara.
关于从前
Um...about before.
我也是一样
Me, too.
恩
Yeah.